UX and product,
um, are two things that should work in
parallel.
Um, product has a lot of UX in it as
well because product, uh, is something
that, uh, stays between, and these are
the three most important topics that go
into product, is UX. So, user experience
in general, user flows, how the user
actually,
um, interacts with the product and feels
it. The tech, because product managers,
uh, usually interact a lot with the, um,
not only developers, but in general,
with how the product is built. And the
business, like sales, pre-sales,
customer support, and so on, and
understanding the needs of the business
and the market and how the product is
positioned there. Okay? So, all of this
part. So, product is an umbrella role,
but you also need UX. And we're going to
talk first about UX.
Um,
and here you can also see a way, um,
other ways to, uh, to look at the tasks
of design and product management, so
that you also know, um,
the roles that you're going to need to
cover in your product. What they both
have in common, and when where we are
getting, is that, um, they can both
assume that the customers will know how
to use it.
As I told you, UX is about how users,
um,
experience the product. So, this
assumption that customers know how to
use it before testing it, before, um,
showing it to them, before actually
testing that hypothesis, it might be
wrong because users, I won't say users
are stupid because, and you shouldn't
say that, either, because that's not
true.
Only designs and experiences are stupid
because you've been building them for
users that, uh, become frustrated when
they use it. So, you should build tools
that are easy to use. And easy to use is
a term that is
used a lot, but never
when it is put on a slide
and you ask about UX and user experience
in general and user research, no one
knows how to answer. They just say, "I
made it easy to use." Or the AI designed
it easy to use. It is not easy to use
until we put it in the hand of a user
and you look at them and see that they
know how to use it. But, what they have
in in common is that they are problem
solvers. So, they solve the problem of
the users. And this is why I also like
the job of product management in general
because there are always problems that
we need to discover from the users'
perspective that we solve through our
solutions. UX has a lot of definitions
from different parts,
but
it is usually
this umbrella term that describes all of
the interactions that the user has with
the product. And why do I say that it's
all of the interactions, all of the
factors? It's because it's not only that
I can use the product. It's how I
perceive it, how I like it. So, if we
think of products such as, I don't know,
the Apple ecosystem, you get used to it
because the experience is smooth. It
solves It solves some of the problems
that you encountered with other
platforms, maybe that they solved along
the way, but
um
you like something also because of the
brand, for example, how they
present themselves, their simplicity,
their innovation.
So, UX is in all of your touch points
with the brand. So, you need to take
care of this user experience or customer
experience in the future not only in how
they interact with your product but also
how you
talk about the product. What's in it for
you to look at UX?
And I wanted to tell you also something
that I mean in the last years this with
UX UI is still a miss
misused term and it is confused.
Usually UX is like a joke. If you have
to explain it, it is not that good.
So and UI is the what you see are the
beautiful parts. The fact here that you
see the Heinz
ketchup bottle on the left hand side it
is nice. It looks good has the logo and
so on. But guess what? Whenever you as a
user of the ketchup bottle you want to
use it, you will keep it the other way
around. Therefore, in order to see the
brand, you need to put the label in the
Yeah, rotate it, right?
And in order to get also the usability
out of it so to make it usable to get
the last bit of ketchup on your pizza,
you will need to make it more
appropriate in terms of how you hold it
and also to allow the the users so to
have this
feature that you get all of the ketchup
out. Otherwise, they will be missing
product the product out of it. A lot of
companies are investing a lot in UX. And
this
is very important because when you
invest $1 in UX at the beginning, the
return on investment is 100 fold.
And how we can look at that the other
way around is that
um
if you don't invest that $1, it is
possible that you will lose 100 in the
future. Because if you haven't tested
your hypothesis from the beginning, you
haven't tested your experience, you
didn't
um allow the users to interact with your
product, then you will lose $100 in
development money. Because you will
develop it, you will ship it, it will
get to users, they won't know how to use
it, so they will never buy again from
you.
And you lose that money that you could
have uh invested in the beginning and uh
won in the future.
>> [snorts]
>> So, usually through UX and thinking
about the user experience and putting
the user first, not building just
because it's cool, you will achieve
everything faster. Your business goals,
uh you will have a higher return on
investment on every um dollar, every
Now, we're talking dollars or money. You
invest time at the moment. That means
money as well. So, let's say an hour of
your time.
And put this 100-fold.
Um and if a customer is happy from the
beginning, from the first time they use
your product, it is easy for them to use
it,
then they will recommend you to others
or they will talk nicely about you. But
if you annoy them, if the experience is
bad, uh if uh the design is bad, then uh
you will need to do uh around uh from
five to seven good deeds after so that
you re-win that customer. These are the
two sides of uh the brain in terms of UX
and UI. So, the UI is visual design,
colors, graphic design, layouts, and
typography, and the rest of it is um the
interaction, doing prototypes,
information architecture, user research,
and so on.